Anthony Rivers

Anthony Rivers

Jersey City, NJ

(908)-294-2646
Software Engineer
hireriversanthon

hireriversanthony@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/rivers-anthony https://github.com/rememberanthonyrivers

Summary

Enthusiastic, charismatic, and inquisitive computer scientist with a strong foundation in data structures, mathematics, and the ability to develop practical solutions that prioritize both performance and security. My education has provided me with a wealth of experience in the areas of web development, database design, and software engineering.

Skills

Languages: Python, Javascript, HTML5, CSS 3, SQL, JSON, JSX, Bash, Git

Software: React, Flask, Django, NodeJS, Microsoft Office Suite

Other: Verbal and written skills, Interdepartmental communication, presentation, financial products and derivatives.

Experience

Software Developer — Coding Temple, Chicago, IL

APRIL 2021 - JULY 2021

- Architected and constructed visually appealing, user-friendly responsive web pages and interfaces using HTML5, CSS 3, and Javascript.
- Collaborated with back-end developers to integrate front-end and back-end code.
- Tested and debugged web pages and interfaces to ensure proper functionality across different browsers and devices.
- Optimized website performance, Stayed up-to-date with new technologies to improve workflow and work quality.
- Worked together with designers to ensure web application aligns with clients vision and brand identity.

Data Analyst — Coding Temple, Chicago, IL

JAN 2021 - APR 2021

- Analyzed and visualized data using Python Libraries like Matplotlib, and Plotly to create insightful charts and graphs.
- Collected and processed data from various sources using Python Libraries such as Pandas and Numpy.
- Skilled in crafting high quality reports and presentation that clearly communicate the results of data analysis to a wide range of stakeholders, including senior management

 Cleaned and transformed data using Python Libraries such as Pandas to ensure accuracy and consistency

Administrative Assistant — H&R Block, Chatham, NJ

FEB 2023 - Present

- Assisted with tax preparation by gathering and organizing client information, inputting data into tax software, printing and mailing tax returns.
- Maintained Accurate and up-to-date client records.
- Handled confidential client information with discretion and ensured that it is securely stored.
- Greeted clients, collected information, and ensured all necessary forms and documentation were completed.

Customer Service Rep / Dietary Associate -The Chelsea At Fanwood Senior Living, Fanwood, NJ

SEPT 2009 - JAN 2023

- Maintained and updated accurate records containing customer information
- Resolved customer complaints: Listened to customer concerns and provided solutions
- Provided support and information between teams in regards to customer records

Education / Achievements

Coding Temple / Python Software Development Certification

Software Development Bootcamp JANUARY 2021-JULY 2021, Chicago, IL

Union College / A.A.S. Computer Science

SEPTEMBER 2018-MAY 2020, Cranford, NJ